like SAP Arena meant came as
certain and you'll see why in a moment,
and the second chamber DisplayPort says
Ley, the third chamber law is about David
Tepper, the fourth chamber law, first of all,
he gives us the
terms, the first is karma,
if you get something good, you get
something good, but if you get something
bad, you get something bad,
the second is that chemical results
multiply, the third law is
if you do nothing, then nothing will happen,
and the fourth is how much do I have to
pay,
it has to be heat, write an emergency text,
where is it sent,
that led, if you plant a chamer,
it won't go away, so
those of you who
teach the three will appreciate the true meaning
much more, and we're
really going slowly,
who taught these four chamber laws, guess,
it goes with bosom,
ends with k
[Music],
they are very, very important for
Buddhist people, the first chamber law,
that can be said for sure, is
set, well, Wiener is
called, it is one of the five major
themes of Buddhist books, and it is
called a  Living an ethical life, and he
quotes her book on
ethical living: no matter what kind of action you take,
the result will
be the same. If you do something
good or nice to other people, then you can only
achieve a good result. This
reader is in the subjunctive mood; then you can
experience no suffering. And the result
if you hurt other people can
only be suffering. It can only be suffering
for you. And that is, if it
is definitely true,
later today in class I could also ask
questions.
But this topic raises many questions.
Someone here in China had problems
with his mother-in-law, an
unusual problem,
and then he decided to
befriend her. He bought a mat for
the shower cubicle with flowers on it.
The first time a user
fell over it, and then he said, "
Now I have broken African law.
I did something nice to my mother-in-
law, and she hates me
more." And we have to talk about this, for example,
if you plant something spicy near the flames.
So if you plant a chili seed,
then everything that
grows from it will be a chili.  So, something
spicy. If you plant something with a
bitter taste, then the result will
always be something bitter. The name
is sweet taste. Like Friedman, you
ask for two in Tibetan. Cap is
like sweet Thurow. It's predetermined. That's why
you have to be
careful when you plant it,
not when you find out the result. That's why you have to
be careful when you
plant the causes. One of the results is
luck. You need to
think about it again. If
one of us gets sick, and no matter
how many treatments we have, seeds
always go in one channel: cause, result, cause,
result. These channels do
n't mix. Those of
you who are interested in this,
Sibel Kekilli: If you plant a chili,
then
if such a chili plant is already determined, and
you don't want a chili, and therefore
plant apples and grapes around the chili, Bednara, the chili won't be sweet.
So, for example, if two or
three people were hurt,
and that was when I was young, and since then
I only plant grapes to be
safe.  But then, with age,
the old color changes so that not every seed
is connected to the result in the future,
and they don't mix.
So if you believe you are a good
person but also have chili seeds,
you must be aware that this
cause and this result
are connected and don't intersect with the
others.
It's very difficult to see the learning process,
but we in Buddhism say it's even more
difficult to understand how karma
works. It's much deeper,
the subtle details. So, according to
the causes you plan, you will
experience the corresponding results.
[Music]
And then he gives another example of
a monk. Currently,
he has a very beautiful voice, and he
knows how to sing.
Sometimes you see beautiful
people in Hollywood who can't sing.
La La Land, sorry, but that guy really can't do it.
And sometimes it's the other way around:
a warm-hearted person with a beautiful
voice. Why did he have an ugly
body and a beautiful voice? In ancient
times, there was a king who built a temple,
and he was born among the
people who were hired to help maintain
the temple.  to build
and he complained when the green
spirit in Pempelfort but damn it, it would be
so big again. He
said negatively about the temple, we'll never finish the temple.
And after the temple was finished, he
went to his teacher in the temple and confessed, "
I
really didn't have a bad opinion about the
temple." And now it's finished and it
's really beautiful, like now in the Ried,
where you wonder why it's so
strenuous, and afterwards you say, "Balls
was really beautiful." And to make amends
[music]
or to pay for the bell for the bell tower,
and that's the example of
Buddha for someone who has a mixed chamber.
He complained and
said negative things, and that's why
he has an ugly body, but then he gave
this bell, and that's why
he doesn't have a beautiful voice. The person who
brought Buddhism to Tibet
is called Party Charme,
and so since then, the Tibetans did
n't know Buddhism yet because he had
n't taught them, and that's why
the people  Around him, they
committed small bad deeds because they didn't yet
know right and wrong,
and they didn't understand that they were doing
something wrong. There's a funny
story about that.
I think I've already
told you, but I'll just tell it again. When
he came to teach the offenders,
he only brought one assistant with him,
and this assistant constantly wanted to avoid
mentioning bad words in class IV, but he was really just a stupid person,
someone who really
annoyed everyone. And then the Tibetans
asked Artie Shaw, "You're the biggest
guru from all of India, and almost 100
people support you, why did
you bring this stupid person?"
Then he said, "Angels, because
my patience isn't very well
developed yet, and every day he challenges
me. He's very, very valuable
to me because he irritates me so much.
I can learn patience from them." And in
Tibet, they had to ride horses and
hike and switch off. A small stone in
his shoe, and he was
just learning Tibetan at the time; he wasn't
really speaking fluently yet.
Like, let's stop for a moment, and
everyone asked why,
but I said I had a rock in
my shoe, but used the wrong word,
or everyone laughed.
His excuse, but I really
adapted. Now I can send my
assistant, the crazy one, to India. From now on,
understood. So the perpetrators did
n't know how to behave
towards a Buddhist teacher. Walked around,
and everything is okay, and Bahn told
one of them, "I ca
n't take it anymore," and to an old monk,
he said, "Don't be so World Judgment
Kramer, it's subtle, karma is profound. The
Tibetans around me make so many
small mistakes, but this touches them
as if it were normal." And he
said, "Don't be too self-confident." He had
the picture; it's picture number 6.
He looks like a normal guy, and we don't
think he's a bad person,
but if he understood karma, then it would be like this,
and that means we
are.
I'm not such a bad person; I
make small mistakes, but I didn't
kill anyone today.
This is a meditation we do together,
so if you really understood karma,
then you would be nervous.  Not going anywhere,
we have about 2000 Munich pillows,
so if everyone brought their own pillow, it would be a
waste
of time and finding your own pillow
would be impossible. We
sewed a number of pillows and
then you simply get assigned a place on
a pillow, and
sometimes even your food takes time.
He put some oil on the pillow there in
Munich, and his robe was
burgundy. In Tibet, you buy
white fabric and then dye it.
He had a big pot and
dyed the fabric there, and then
loads of people ran towards him.
I think he was... and the police
said okay, let it be investigated otherwise.
And then they took a stick, put it
in the water, and then
a piece comes out, and
the witch... and then he said he
stole my cow, and then they
beat him.
It's a famous story in Tibet.
He has no more pain. He
dyed his red. There was no cow in the pot.
And when they were over 15, Nico was in there,
and that's because in his
previous life he stole a cow,
ultimately able to turn clothes into a cow
because of my father.
So if you do something nice for other
people now and they don't understand
you, then you shouldn't
be surprised. They don't see you the way you see yourself
because of the things you did in the
past. This happens quite
often in our lives. Now, something
neutral, something nice, and many
people understand us because they
perceive something different—
the manatee. And it's a real cow. That's how
strong karma is, how people don't
perceive it. It comes from how you
behaved in the past. Your
reality changes because of your
seeds. Very interesting, and they were
locked in prison for six months.
[Music]
And then there's another
story about a worker who used to
steal a calf, and over six
days... So we're now doing a
meditation about boiling laundry. That means
if you have the karma, if you're good,
people will see everything,
perceive it as if you did something bad
because of your chamber. What happens to the
new ones?  Chambers next time you
play the cow game, think the people cook his
laundry. There's
a city called [unclear], without why
is the city so famous? The root of the
word [unclear] is [unclear], travesty. There,
Buddha taught the diamond cutter. There was
a nobleman, and his name was
Marga, and he had another [unclear], he had a
relative who [unclear] actively, and she gave birth to 32
children, very, very healthy children. And
then there was a king who got his
friends and the ministers into
trouble, and because of that,
the king killed the 32 children,
and he brought the mother's heads
to hurt her.
And that has to do with something these
32 children did in their previous lives.
These 32 stole a cow together
and killed it. And there was
a time when the wife of a guesthouse
owner did
something to encourage them,
and that's his way of
learning the first chamber law: what you
do comes back to you, and it's
always the same in this [unclear], so
people  Those who paid money to
comment on this are nice people.
Bad people don't pay money
to hear the pen. Most
people who come to this are
really nice people, and they are
spiritual people, and they try to do
good for other people.
So they try to help someone, and
then something bad happens. In this
system, you have to understand that it
comes from something you did before.
That has no connection to
its good partner
in my life. If I have tried
to do something good and it has a
bad result, then sometimes I feel like
I'm not even
trying to do good things anymore. And
you really have to understand that good
makes good and bad makes
bad. So if you
try to do something good for someone, and something
bad happens, you shouldn't
believe that the bad comes from the good.
And you should never be discouraged.
You try to do what goes wrong. Do
n't let the brave try to
understand where it really comes from.
And now we're talking about the second
chamber law. This can multiply.
How does chambers earn their keep? There is
the possibility that
seeds of a result produce something outside, for example,
in nature.  Then there is the
possibility of generating a result in
a mind,
and he says the inner ones multiply
more.
He explains to her that in Tibetan, he says they
multiply more, and that is
the name of the second law,
the second law, the name of the second law,
so multiply more, and the way
he explains it, he says inner
reasons produce greater results
than outer ones. If you take the kernel of a 40-gram tree
and you plant it,
then it will become a large tree,
and that's what we're talking about in this style.
In North America, there is an oak tree that
weighs 45 grams, and that yields
5000 tons, or 3000 kilos. Sorry, 3000
kilos. My name is... So, what he taught was that they
ate 40
in New Jersey. Back then, there was
no global
warming, and yet it still snowed,
and at those few degrees,
he planned for the guys, and if you
visit our temple now, it is
truly a beautiful, large tree.
Demands kitchen reform. Kissing fans. He
planted it.
You can go and Indira  Look, and
each tree produces many more ladies,
and branches come out of the trunk, and leaves and flowers come out of them,
and from these
the fruits develop, and from these come
the new flags,
and according to Buddha, he went to a special
state, and the name of the city of mangoes is
there, and it is also the name of a
special tree. I think out there,
that's new Kalisz, but after, or it
grows and replants itself,
and it replants itself. It
can spread for many
miles,
and then there was a woman who brought him
a gift, a chocolate, probably
already with her. She will call it
Lotto, a French pastry in
Tibet, and Tempo Gabi, a handful of
these sweets
and butter, then said it is his
kind,
and the name of the 8th will be his super hit,
and then her husband got upset.
She said, "Mother said to everything," and
he criticized Buddha and said, "
You shouldn't lie to come back to a
couple," and then he went
with him to the tree. How big
is it?  Seed of this tree and the
husband showed that it is as big as
a mustard seed and how big is the tree
now,
speaking of which, that's what comes from, the five tons,
the 3, 5 tons, the story, and then he said,
or said, recently we
parked 500 cars under the tree and the
wheels didn't touch,
and where that said in spirit, the
farm is stronger, and then the husband
said, okay, now I believe you, and there was
one similar to what we
criticized another for, when you sing it sounds
like someone is torturing a dog with a
knife, but not always, sometimes it
also sounds like a frog, but the one
you can easily make with your left hand, just like the
squeaking of monkeys, and when the
man died, he had three
rebirths as 100 frogs and a
monkey,
and that's really, this
story is very famous in
Buddhism,
it's not unusual that we do it five
or six times a day, which isn't entirely
without someone saying,
every time you slip and a
small incompleteness  Sachs, can this create a
complete rebirth of 70 or 80 years
from a small slip-up
in China? Now, cinema mentioned someone
wrote a book titled "
People Who Are Snakes,"
in which the other
Buddhist masters of his time are criticized, and they
all know how snakes are.
The author of the book later got
a very strange illness where the
skin between his arms and
body grew like a house, and his
head suddenly looked like a snake.
And La Massa, I really
saw a person who didn't die,
but became a snake during his lifetime.
Voldemort doesn't say his name,
and we've heard this story before, about
the fishermen who
caught a huge fish, as big as a whale, and it took 500
men to reach a country.
The whale had 18 heads, and
that's a really famous story.
Then the brother came to the beach,
and people breathed... What was his karma?
What is the karma of this fish?  And
here they don't tell the whole
story.
I told the story about
five years ago, so
I don't have to tell the whole
story. But briefly
summarized, and I said you don't have to ask me
what he did.
Then he used a magic trick
and the whale could suddenly
speak.
In his past life, he had a
mother who wasn't really my type,
and she bravely told him
to tell Munich that they behaved like dogs. That's why
he was
reborn in this body.
When he saw that the ball
was on the beach, he recognized it and went there
because he saw that he
could teach someone something with it. And
for that, he was criticized.
He was criticized for it. People
accused him of just being greedy.
I told you the story when
we learned the preparatory exercises. There's
an expression: "Into the beds with
Daggi, shoot targets at the rider with
an arrow and tracks the horse's work."
That means actually hurting someone,
like hitting someone ten times with a
pistol.
So look at that. Nobody here
in the room is going to hit someone ten times.  Someone
shoots with a pistol,
but we say such small critical
words to others that I stupidly only drive for
a few seconds to see
who is that, that's
the tongue, it's very soft,
it's not like a stick, but still
you can break a person's heart with it,
that it's a quote from Benjamin
Franklin and he says the same thing, it's not
how you kill them, you say it's
still very small, but it hurts
them very much. I think I told you this story
here on the L'Aquila
course.
It's a long tragic story
about a woman who was forced by her husband
to help her baby,
and that was only the beginning of her
difficulties. The story is
unbelievable, so very much so.
The two children, after that
they had two more children,
one was swept away by a tidal wave, one was eaten
by a wolf,
her husband was killed by a snake,
and her parents died in a
fire, and later she saw
one of these wandering around
when
they had a baby together, and the
husband went to party with them.  He was with friends and
got drunk, and when he
came back, he forced the woman to
kill the baby and eat his flesh.
Then she went crazy
and ran away. Later, when she recovered,
she
met a king who had just
died, and then she married him. Back then,
it was customary that when the
husband died, the wife was killed
when they buried him,
and even today, it's sometimes still done. So,
if
someone bothers you and they burn the woman, they
often burn her too.
She was put in the grave with her husband, and
the jewels were taken away. Sorry, but one day
the grave robber was caught by the king and killed.
Then they
tried to bury her a second time,
and all of this came about because of her own actions.
In a previous life, she was, how do you
say it, the chief wife
of a king with many other wives, and
she was very jealous of one of the
younger wives.
Therefore, she invented stories about
the younger wife, and all of this was a
result of everything she did.
I even believe she
murdered the child of the younger wife. Speaking of the ending,
which they never tell, the
ending is that she went completely insane
and then she collapsed.
He spent many years trying to heal
her, and later she became a
kind of... In the same life,
they were without... And then... Aha, that's
really a very beautiful story.
I think I'd like to stop here and
do a little meditation with you,
and then we'll take a break.
Now we'll do a meditation. Can
you... The picture number two
shows a husband that all husbands should do:
he doesn't wash the dishes, but he
even smiles while doing it. So, if you
get a manual today or tomorrow or in any other century...  I want you to
remember the pictures.
The picture with the crisis war is simply
that it's the first picture. You'll
remember Syria.
And then there was a woman
thinking about her farms, and
then there was a little boy holding
his father. It means that the
boy, Karl Ernst, understands basic protection.
And now it's the second meditation. In
total, he gets 30. What is
the story? Could that be expected after
this morning's class? No good
seeds. Yes, that too. But also the banker
in the budget said, also a banker
said, it's not enough to be an expert in
Buddhist books.
It's not enough to be represented for three years.
It's not enough
to talk about teachers all day.
You also have to be nice to the next other
people.
Sometimes it's really irritating
to be surrounded by Buddhists in the house.
My lama said it was necessary that he invited
the students to dinner every two weeks,
and I and the other
assistant said a prayer. We had all the
Buddhist students come.
We will eat for three hours, and
Then everyone says I have so much to do, I ca
n't help with the washing up now, and
sometimes we were up at 2 a.m., the
rooms still weren't finished, and I've been doing
them for 25 years. I really was
more than that. The Buddhists talked
about emptying the toilets all evening.
We can reproduce the smallest detail, all the
ideas, superiority,
but they didn't even know how to wash up. What
he said was, if you
understand the toilet, then you have to do something.
It's not enough to use it. Study.
I was in Shanghai and I think I met them all.
We did the letters, Peter Restaurant,
and she said
maybe I was at the retreat, and I
almost got sick back then. What is a toilet?
I asked her.
You have to. I also had to. Friedrich has to
go to every toilet, but I
forgot how to do the washing up.
So we're going to meditate on it now.
Think about it. What is my practice?
Now you have to study. Do yoga,
do meditations, and help
people wash up and clean up again. We're meditating
now. In the last two or
three days, think about practical things. Have
you helped?
We went to  For
example, we just left a real mess in the music room
because the
Buddhist teacher had to rush into
class. I don't know who's cleaning up;
he'll probably do the dishes when he
comes tonight.
[Music]
We're starting meditation now.
I'll guide you. It only takes five
minutes, then we'll take a break.
And I want him to think about whether I'm
helpful. I know maybe a
lot. I do my practice, but am I
helpful?
Because the lama in the book says if you
truly understand karma, then
you should be helpful. Dusting off,
all the dirty work for a retreat,
jeans, and needs help now.
She's taking care of the fire offering.
We have 22 fires in this. A lot of work. It's
really fun throwing the stuff into the fire,
but it takes many days to
prepare all of that. Think about it.
So if you truly
understand Buddhism, then you understand karma. If
you understand karma, then part of
your life is to serve other people, to
help with the little things.
And if someone says they are a  Great
yoga or a good doctor, but they do
n't know how to wash dishes? That should make
you critical.
I washed all the dishes for eight years,
sometimes there were two or three hundred
people there.
My secret initiation was a
dishwashing initiation, and I think it
helped me a lot.
I think that's why I became a better
person.
Sometimes I wish I could do that
with you too,
but I don't have that many valleys. So
meditate and then take a break, relax
your hands, relax your forehead, a gentle smile,
also
draw your forehead in slightly, then down your forehead,
smooth it out, and then concentrate
on your breath.
We observe the breath for a few minutes, let it
relax,
let the outside world come to this
one point in your mind.
It's a very simple meditation.
What can I do to help with this retweet? It ca
n't be helpful,
not just meditating, not just studying,
not just doing yoga.
How can I help the people who
organize the retreat?
How can I plant all these little seeds
that ultimately
make the meditation successful?
How can I make this retreat in the
next  On days like these, we'll now do this for
five minutes.
Of course, you want to think about other things,
but just try to bring your
concentration back and make a
very precise plan. How can I
help at this retreat?
Focus again on your breath.
Three long exhales.
Then you could open your eyes.
My lover forced me to
cook for all the monks for eight years.
I actually wanted to learn philosophy.
No, no, he said, you're the cook.
And my hands were
completely raw from bleeding so much. I had
special gloves. He was really
strict with me. I had to clean the whole house
and the whole world, mow the lawn, and take care of
his stupid flowers. No,
it wasn't stupid.
He simply forced me to
process it, and today I understand that
it was really good.
I encourage you who are lazy and want to
study philosophy, but not while doing the dishes. Don't worry about
the height. What I'm
saying right now is something wrong with your
ears.
But you will never have successful
meditations or understand the majority
if you don't help with the
dirty work. It won't happen,
and I thank
my lama. I believe  Finally, he
even met me before I did. He was really
strict.
Remember, don't expect
people to ask you for help. There are some
people who are simply there,
who are always ready to help,
and then there are those who find
time to tidy up. If she's gone, it becomes
truly magical, and then you'll never be
successful in a practice if you do
n't help with the normal things. But
if you do, then it can be like the great
Jogi Werthner. There's no
other way. Okay, then we'll take a
break now, Olga, or stand up.
She'll ask if she has any work for you, and don't
expect her to ask you. And
if you ask her, then that shows that you've understood
the class. Let's
continue.
We need a microphone for the
translator, please. I showered this morning,
but Monika needs support.
Okay, with me. There are
many stories I
can tell you.
Understanding the chemical seeds is more
difficult than understanding the majority,
and here's the corresponding quote:
Someone has to give me the internet password afterward.
Even a person who isn't yet a body,
although they can understand the apprenticeship,
and  They can also
teach them, but only a Buddha
can perfectly learn the teaching time. People like you,
we have to
use and study the logic to
truly understand Khama.
And then he starts talking about doing
small, bad
deeds.
The test of whether a person
understands Buddhism is how they deal with small
mistakes,
little lies, or cheating someone a little.
If they avoid that, it's a
sign that they are true Buddhists.
And then he quotes a book—it's
a collection of stories. Do
n't think that all the small bad
deeds you've done to others are forgotten.
Because if you put a big pot under the
drain and the sink, and it
drips, a big, big bag of bad deeds will eventually
overflow.
People who haven't directly perceived the majority yet
usually hear all these small drops
of bad deeds, and that's what ultimately
hurts them.
I call that the blue topaz question.
I worked in the diamond business for 19 years.
Every day we
checked 300 diamonds outside. Half of them
dealt with...  Diamonds and the
other half of the department
deals with other gemstones, and we were
looking for light blue stones, and there are
no naturally occurring
light blue gemstones. Zafira is too
dark, and a light sapphire is very, very
rare. Then we heard about a
guy in Hong Kong who
found a way to make blue gemstones.
We call them topaz. In
nature, it's available in brown,
but if you irradiate it in a
nuclear reactor, it
turns a very, very beautiful blue.
Nowadays, you can find it everywhere,
and we heard that he
invented it, but he kept the method
secret. I found out
who was doing it, and we
found a reactor in Switzerland, and I sent them 50 stones,
and they made them blue.
Then I said, "You can send them
back to me."
Then they said, "Yes, in 1904 years,
I can send them back."
The half-life is about ten years,
so the radiation halves every
ten years. And they would have said, "Forget it."
And then I found out what...
You can buy a certain stone from Sri Lanka, it's not irradiated, it takes
three weeks to
use,
and I have many pregnant women in
my department, similar to the Mexico
virus,
and I was worried about them, so
I
called the government's radiation department.
Is this stone safe? Yes, yes, we
approve it, we approved it.
He pulled a stone into a... I'm not talking about
one stone,
we have such big bags of them, 14,
15,000 stones. And then the guy
said, my proximity... that's a real
problem. One stone wo
n't hurt you, but
5,000, 10,000 together... so, small
bad karma. It's not blue topaz, one wo
n't hurt you, but
every day with ten or twenty of them...
but like water drops in a pot, it
will destroy you,
it will destroy your life. The small ones did
n't... the big ones... and
he talks about that even more. It's the same
with the small good karma.
If you always do the dishes, you do
the small good
things, three or four every day, they will turn
one into butter, so do
n't do that.  Great, wonderful deeds that
make me a brother, it's the little ones, there are so
many little ones. We
always read in books about these monks, the
monk was in the cave or did
n't eat for twelve years and then met Real.
I was my teacher's class for 25
years and I myself had many
students. For 40 years I've observed
students and it's those who do the
small good things, who will become
wonderful people, those who say no,
I don't want to make a weekend public,
I'll do that right away. Three years too sweet, those who
do the dishes, those who become
bodyguards, that was the factor, those who
help the retreat and that's why his class should
miss out, that's why those are the ones who will
leave, what will become?
I didn't say that he
should miss a class, the
mother had a student better
than Mr. Where is one of our big
sponsors? The butter is like this, when he
opens the edge, then the gold grows, it
simply comes into his hand, and his
name was Herbold. Why did he find out?
He sold a tree in his
previous life and he received a gold coin
for it.  He had
put them in a water jug,
I don't know why,
and he saw it where the victims of the one who was there
before our brother and the helper
Apa had been, and that's why
gold always seemed to be in his hands. And
then there was an older one, namely his
name is Canada Vasco, which means "the
golden calf." When he experienced it in
his storeroom,
seven golden elephants appeared in his house. And
now comes the nice part:
every time they peed or defecated,
gold came out, and that's how he became rich.
And then there was an evil king, the
Adapter, and the king later killed
his own father.
He stole the elephants seven times, kidnapped them, and took them to
his palace. He
locked them in a special room, and then they
sank into the ground and simply
disappeared.
And then they reappeared in the guy's
house
seven times. So the evil king could
n't steal the elephant with the golden bottom.
And the reason he got the golden cows
in the previous life was something
else.  Mother of
Harmony, who rode around on an elephant,
and someone made him a
small statue of his elephant out of
clay, and someone broke the clay elephant,
and the guy snapped the
broken trunk of the elephant
back together, and he
painted it gold, not real gold but just
gold-colored, and because of these small
chamber HD7 gold doll elephants,
there was a nun who, now in the time of the
Buddha, was
born to her mother and
already had wonderful silk robes on,
and later she became a
nun and her clothes
automatically turned into robes, she did
n't have to buy them, why? In a
previous life, she was
the wife of a man, and they
were both very poor, so poor that
they only had a piece of cloth to
cover themselves with,
and if he was ever in India, twist what
I'm talking about,
on Tuesday he covered himself with the cloth
and went to work, and on
Wednesday finally, covered with the same
cloth, went to work because they
only had one  Cloth, rats, and the like,
or cardamom, and they brought this
piece of cloth as a gift
even though it was very cold, and that's why
she was
reborn with automatic clothes.
Honky-tonk, there is karma where you get a
better result in this outcome,
so the king gave them
wonderful clothes. The point of the
story is that if you have the chance to
do a small good deed, like
making a cappuccino for someone in the class (not
for me, I already have), do it for
someone else sitting here in the class,
or bring them tea, open
the door for them, give
them a pillow, or make room if
they're not looking at the teacher, you
should always look out for
these small
acts of kindness. So
if someone
is a big Buddhist yogi, they always look for
a small good opportunity to
help someone in a small way.
This is a sign that the
chamber understands because it doubles every 24
hours.
You can accumulate a lot of four chambers
if  You do small things, the same
will be this book about the collection,
about the collection of small
stories,
that has already done it, he quotes it again:
if you do small good things, do
n't think that only small results will
come back.
So if you put that big pot under
the leaking pipe, then it will be
filled.
I think the last verse choice about
bad deeds, this verse about small
good deeds, wise people collect these
small good deeds. Partners of those of
you who learn poetically are,
because a balanced person is...
before, I had... which word did
you remember? It was... what is that? There's
an interesting...
before Buddhism,
it's a theme. We have a translation
team in Arizona
[music].
We translate every day for many, many
hours, and I
asked some of them to report on the book
they are currently translating.
Two of them are more
Spanish-speaking: Takahashi and Niklas. During
the retreat, I'm taking a
break from classes. Also, my partner
from Arizona is coming. I have to go to the airport and
pick up the bus.
Nick will be a...  Give a class on his book, it
's a very cool book by Magath,
already that he's translating it, and she's
translating a book called "Measuring the Crown,"
and some nice people
from Austria asked me to
translate a book about karma.
Aldi connects all the Amish
correlations, and there's a long
list of Fischer's teacher, and Sille is
translating that,
and he's going to give a class on it.
This word came into our books, dear,
what does it mean? You can translate it academically as "
baby between one and
two years old," Nicolas Kiefer, but in colloquial
English in
North America, they say "you" as if you behave
like a two-year-old, and exactly, it means that it's
for someone who has
n't directly experienced the majority yet. So, a two-
year-old behaves as if there are
two, yes, the old children collect
bad karma like a dripping
faucet, but unfavorably, wise people
collect good karma like drops
of water. Let's make tea,
open a door, carry a bag, and
if you do many small good deeds, by doing so, you become
Buddha,
everyone is waiting for something big, for something
big to happen, but it's the
little things, many, many little
things, and that's how you'll become a butter.
Okay, even if you've only learned the first two
of the four karmas, then you should
be totally excited and say, "I want to do
as many good little deeds as
possible." I like it when Buddhists
correct themselves when they speak.
Someone asked me how many
people came to my Singapore lecture.
I believe only 1200, and according to
my mind, almost 2000. But
a real butter, the 21, was actually
only 1000, because they correct themselves
like autocorrect every few minutes.
They really try to speak the truth, they
try to
avoid the small, bad karma. Decide to do that
now. I'll stop
here now. Now we'll
continue with the third chamber law. I promised
to answer your questions, but haven't done so yet. So
we'll do ten minutes of
questions and answers. So tonight
I'll start with the questions.
So if you can't ask the question now,
then we'll do it tonight.
Salla, so God willing,
thank you Bachelor for these wonderful
lessons. I have two questions before
basic SAP: What caused the
drowsiness during meditation?
I think I felt it completely without understanding, I don't know
why.
Maybe I'm just thinking... Residents,
please consider... no more donath, that
's not good for me.
I really like this question. Why?
Recently, someone in
this program asked me what the
difference is between the meditation that
Duh teaches and the meditation
taught in other places, like Pasta or something. What
is the difference?
The difference is very, very
interesting, and it's related to the question with a touch of irony.
In the higher schools of Buddhism,
all external things come from karma. That
's simple. But internal things
give rise to thoughts like the ones you have in your
own mind. There's
a famous question about this: Do
you speak these thoughts or do you listen to
these thoughts? Because you can't do both at the same time. It's not possible to be the
speaker in your mind, or are you the
listener? Which one are you?
Or, you said, you are the listener.
Who speaks the seeds? I would
cut you off now if it weren't so far away.
I always say this to
students. Don't be afraid. If
the guy has a beard, they're safe
from me. These thoughts come from your
name.
I don't like this class. The class
lasts too long.
The guy talks too much. Why? Now stop
these thoughts.  When they appear in a
mind because you
talked too much to your friends last week,
blah blah blah blah blah blah blah, and they
wanted to say something but they did
n't get a chance, and so you
planted blah blah blah farms, and next
week you're always at a retreat,
and Gisela says, "Think about all the
great things, do these for Olga, do this,"
and then the mind goes blah blah blah blah blah blah
blah about other things,
better, that's called
being excited in meditation. There are
two big enemies in
meditation:
the first is too much blah blah,
the second, that's obvious, sometimes it's like this,
and the worst part is,
you're like this, but inside you're
kissed through to the point of being
totally stupid. You can sit like this for two or
three hours and you won't
make any progress. You're violating your
meditation. Meditation should be like a Star
Wars movie, that's how
the mini-station should be.
I know a little bit of your Leyen, even in
Paraguay, in America, because people have to
wish they like to
eat popcorn from the movie, held on to it, and they go to
him.  A love movie, and throughout the
whole movie they're eating, and as in
good love movies, at the beginning the
boy doesn't like the girl,
and the filmmakers know that after
an hour and three minutes, the
first lesson should take place. After an hour and
three minutes,
the guy who didn't want the girl
should then give the girl a lesson,
and everyone knows that it's coming,
and it's magic, very slowly and
suddenly, all the popcorn leads to this:
red meditation, his mind.
So, their question is, this sleepy mind,
American space builds dullness, and
many people confuse this state
with good meditation because you ca
n't sit like that for an hour and you
're not sleepy, you're just...
you're not thinking anything, and it's a
big problem in meditation. As a
question, it's very wise:
what is it that came about that the plant that,
when the farm in a mind, sprouts,
you're just a few lazy space builds.
Sleepiness is worse than space builds.
I have an interesting suggestion:
make other people's lives more
interesting, and I'll give you a
famous example from... I have a
list of the boredom shops in...  This world's
number one on my list is, for example, you
work in the parking lot at the
airport and collect money from people
at the small airport. At the
small airport, every half hour
a car comes. How much? Two dollars.
Thank you, have a nice day.
And then you wait another half hour.
I think that's the most boring
job. Working in a supermarket is similar.
People die,
their cell dies. Say something to them. Do
n't treat them like robots. Say
hello. I have a very popular trick, where
a political trick, a
Buddhist spiritual trick. I
will... I stop my car and I saw
how 42 dollars...
I hold the two dollars. So,
excuse me, I have to
go to the movies with my wife tonight, but I have
no idea what good movie is
playing.
Can you help me? Please help. Do
n't give them the money. Have you
seen any good movies? Someone is
talking to me. Yes, everyone has
seen some movie.
I saw Transformers yesterday, it was
good.
Yes, what happened? And they
waited behind them. Six cars and the...
adapted. What about the guys?
Okay, he saved the world six times. Does
that make life...  from other people
interesting
and then it will be because in
meditation your mind will not be sleepy,
it will be clear and you do
n't have to put in much effort,
these little drops will connect
even if you are tired, even if you are bored yourself, do that, the
life of other people
becomes interesting and a meditation will
improve and what I now
distinguish between this meditation
of people from other systems,
we believe that having a good meditation does
not depend on which top
associations in Jena people have
told me if you don't
raise your right foot first, if you
put your left foot up first, then
you will never become a Buddha and you
have to sit like this, no, no,
you have to hold your hands like this to become
my brother or it has to be like this
or you have to look at your nose, in
our system you have to give
other people peace
last week, then you have a good
meditation this week because even the
medication exceptions in a mind
come through the duh last week with
the parking attendant,
okay, that's the difference,
we believe that  Everything from the chamber
also includes a meditation.